You said Bitcoin has 400 to 500x left in
it. Humans are currently trying to save
and store and later exchange 400 to 500
trillion dollars worth of value. What
being human is is an ability to price
tomorrow. An ability to lower our time
preference, innovate and create value
today and bring it with us tomorrow. And
money is the technology that enables us
to do that. And the United States job is
to export dollars to the world. So the
United States instead of producing
things locally and exporting those
things to other countries, it just
exported US dollars and imported real
goods and services. If you are not so
panicked to think how am I going to be
able to afford this house? How am I
going to be able to afford this
vacation? If you are given more
confidence and an ability to save and
future plan for yourself, then society
gets generally better. You own zero
dollars. I wouldn't want to own much if
any of the thing that has historically
only gone down and of the thing that's
been historically the most performant. I
want to own as much as I possibly can. A
median home in the US was 1.8 million
bitcoins. Now a median host house today
in the United States is 4.7 bitcoin. So
obviously if you're saving in a harder
money then the life around you has
historically gotten cheaper.
[Music]
She's the queen of the game. Stacking
crypto like the fame. If you want
success, then take a look away.
It's a great privilege to welcome back
Mer, CEO of Strike and now co-founder
and CEO of a new venture, 21 Capital.
It's backed by uh a number of companies
including Tether, SoftBank Group. It's
expected to launch with over 42,000
bitcoins and it's expected to be well
we'll get Jack to comment on this but
the vision I believe is to have one of
the largest most um exclusive invest
institutional investment vehicles for
Bitcoin. So we'll talk about that with
Jack. And joining me to discuss this is
co-host Bonnie Chang, host of the
Blonnie Blockchain channel. Welcome
Jack. Welcome back. Thanks for being
here. David, thanks for having me back
brother. Good to see you. And Bonnie,
it's a pleasure and honor to meet you.
I'm excited to chat with you both. Let's
do it. Awesome. Super excited. So, okay.
First question. I've watched so many of
your interviews and you said in one of
your interview that US dollar's
purchasing power can only go down over
time and US is forced to weaken its
currency. Do you think this alone will
naturally push the world toward Bitcoin
as a shared global money or does it take
major financial crisis or war to trigger
that shift? Yeah, I I think that uh
money is competitive in a free market to
serve a particular purpose. Uh money is
a market good just like a cheeseburger,
just like an airplane, just like a
house. Except money is different in that
you don't consume the market good. So I
acquire a cheeseburger because I need to
eat it. I acquire a house because I need
to live in it. I acquire an airplane
because I need to travel. I acquire
money because I need to save, store, and
then later exchange my time, energy, my
effort, my labor. And so money serves a
very particular purpose within the
marketplace. And I believe like any
other market good, it's competitive. And
so a dramatic event like a war, like
some political fighting, or even the
macro environment we're living in today
can greatly expedite a monetary regime
change. But I think naturally human
beings seek out the best money because
it is a technology we invented to solve
a very particular problem within the
marketplace. And I naturally think
something like Bitcoin fulfills a lot of
the properties that humans look for in a
money to acquire to save and exchange
their time and energy.
And in your interview with Anthony
Pmplo, you said Bitcoin has 400 to 500x
left in it. Bitcoiners love it. no
coiners probably hate it and call it
crazy. What is the rationale behind this
number? Yeah, so I I want to make sure
my lawyers hear me say I I'm definitely
not making any price predictions on this
podcast, but what I do think is
interesting is trying to understand what
Bitcoin is, what it's solving for, and
the size of the opportunity that it's
going after. Because I think Bitcoin is
often unfortunately coupled with the
NASDAQ, with the stock market, even with
other cryptocurrencies to where in which
I think it's actually a vastly bigger
deal and innovation than how people size
it up. Uh my math is human beings own
roughly a little over 900 trillion worth
of stuff. So that
means currencies, sovereign debt, real
estate, precious metals, collectibles,
like all of the things that we own, fine
art, right? It's about over $900
trillion. Half of that humans are using
as a savings account. So they've what we
call monetized that asset. So they own
the house, not to live in it, but to
actually save the bonus that they got or
save the inheritance money that they
got. They own the art not because they
think it's worth $10 million of art, but
because they're trying to actually save
$10 million and persist it through time.
So, you can roughly estimate that humans
are currently trying to save and store
and later exchange 400 to 500 trillion
dollars worth of value. And where I see
Bitcoin is the ultimate vehicle for
humans to store and then later exchange
the value we create. A lot of what being
human is is an ability to price
tomorrow, an ability to lower our time
preference, innovate and create value
today and bring it with us tomorrow. And
money is the technology that enables us
to do that. And so when I say, you know,
Bitcoin is actually the most ambitious
technology today, the entire equities
market is only $150 trillion. So even if
someone like Facebook or Amazon or AI
were to be the most successful equity
ever and soak up all the equities value,
it wouldn't even come close to half of
Bitcoin's opportunity. So when people
compare Bitcoin to another
cryptocurrency like Ethereum or to
another equity like a Tesla, they're
actually vastly misunderstanding this
the opportunity and the size that is in
amazing money for our species. And so if
Ethereum were to become the next Amazon,
Amazon's only worth$ one and a half
trillion dollars. It's a rounding error
compared to what Bitcoin is trying to
do. Awesome. Um before I pass it back to
Bonnie, but some shorter term uh macro
trends that have uh kind of spooked
Bitcoin investors, though. I mean,
you're right. longer term, there's a lot
of brightness ahead for Bitcoin's
future. But in the first three months of
Trump's presidency, we've gotten pretty
much nowhere in terms of price
appreciation, which has frustrated a lot
of Bitcoin bulls because people were
expecting the new administration to
bring on a new era of new all-time
highs. But that happened before the
election. Were you surprised first and
foremost at Bitcoin's performance year
to date? Uh, I would say not
necessarily. I think the market what the
market got wrong is uh post Trump's
inauguration he was actually liquidity
negative not liquidity positive but the
reason that that was the case goes all
the way back to World War II in my
opinion to understand the macro
environment we're in today we have to
look at monetary history post the world
wars America was the strongest economy
and owned the most gold and so America
actually took on the responsibility of
being the world reserve currency
effectively exporting its strength
through the dollar And what that did for
other economies and other nations that
were frankly decimated was it provided
some form of strength and a relationship
for them to grow back. These are Russia,
China, Germany, Japan. So being the
world reserve currency in the United
States taking on that responsibility, it
actually implies things like a deficit,
David, right? Because the the world now
needs US dollars. It is the medium of
exchange. It is the unit of account. It
is the world reserve currency. And the
United States job is to export dollars
to the world. So the United States
instead of producing things locally and
exporting those things to other
countries, it just exported US dollars
and imported real goods and services. So
oil, energy, raw materials, manufactured
materials like iPhones and microphones
and headphones. And so the US was
constantly sending out dollars importing
goods and services. So effectively what
we've done is we've delegated the
ability to produce real stuff like
Russia is the greatest uh natural uh
resource producer in the world. China is
the greatest manufacturer in the world.
Germany creates the best cars. The US
doesn't create much of anything anymore
for this very structural reason except
for financial markets. And so the
reality is this is not a very
sustainable practice. Printing pieces of
paper out of thin air in exchange for
real goods and services is not a
relationship that is to be sustained. It
actually was a reaction to a decimating
world war. And so what I think we're
living through is the unwind of that.
When you see President Trump say things
like we need to fix our deficits. We
need to bring back a middle class. We
need to bring back a manufacturing
class. We need to be able to produce our
own stuff. is because there is a global
trade imbalance happening where China's
running a trade surplus of something to
the tune of a trillion dollars a year
and the US given this economic alignment
globally has racked up over $35 trillion
worth of debt and there are no marginal
lenders to the United States anymore.
We're on the brink of a sovereign debt
crisis. And so I think that there's a
lot of volatility and there's a lot of
trade flow reordering that we're living
through today and investors trying to
predict when these things are liquidity
positive, liquidity negative, ne
negative, how the volatility is going to
impact certain structural markets. It's
a very dangerous game to play. I think
investors were probably caught offside
for the first 3 months of Trump's
inauguration because he's been so pro
business, so pro growth, so pro
deregulation that they probably got
ahead of their skis. Um, but now we're
starting to really understand uh how the
world needs to realign, the impacts of
that, and just the true power that a
fixed supply asset like a gold or a
bitcoin could have in a portfolio. If I
could just drill down a bit deeper and
talk about the things or assets that
actually drive the Bitcoin price. Take a
look at my screen here. People have
commented on the correlation between
Bitcoin and the stock market. Uh, this
is the Bitcoin price. Let me just
overlay this with S&P. Uh generally
speaking over the last 5 years I believe
the correlation coefficient is close to
70%. People have commented in early
April after liberation day when tariffs
were announced that the correlation
broke down momentarily when Bitcoin went
up while the stock market went down. Uh
they've both re um converged since then.
Uh so that's one narrative. The other
narrative is per people like Lyn Alden
who's done research on this the Bitcoin
price is more correlated with the global
M2 money supply. So liquidity is a
better barometer
um of Bitcoin's price action than
actually what's going on with the stock
market. Can you just evaluate both of
these statements? Yeah, I actually agree
probably more with Lynn. I think that
like listen uh this microphone I'm
talking to you with is correlated to the
stock market. Uh my coffee mug here is
correlated to the stock market.
Everything has gone up in dollar terms
and so being correlated to the stock
market just means you're appreciating
against a currency that's being
devalued. So, I think it's too grandiose
of a statement to take seriously. The
reality that I think is absolutely true
is Bitcoin is the most accessible liquid
smoke alarm for fiat liquidity. My
general mental model individually is
that Bitcoin equals technology plus fiat
liquidity. It equals the technological
advancement of things like cryptography,
distributed networks, plus the more fiat
currency units that need to be issued
for governments to remain solvent in an
existing financial system to transition
to something new. And so I think Bitcoin
is most sensitive to global liquidity,
but so is the stock market. Like David,
if we were to go back to the macro
environment I just laid out where
countries like China are living in a
trillion dollar annual trade surplus,
that capital can't be invested locally.
That capital has because I if you're
looking to be competitive in exports,
you can't have a powerful strong local
currency. So when China is making
profits in global trade, they have to
invest it outside of the country. And a
lot of that trade surplus has found
itself in the US stock market in US real
estate. So this is why US you know um US
dominance and US exceptionalism has been
funded by the trade surplus of our
global peers and the fact that US assets
are so inflated in price and that
there's such a difference between the
wealth gap and the lower class and the
upper class. It's all a result of the
current economic relationships and world
reserve currency status and so on and so
forth. So, I think these things are all
generally correlated to fiat liquidity
and unwinding from that is going to be
very dangerous. I think the NASDAQ, for
example, I do expect Bitcoin to
potentially decorrelate in the future
because, you know, if if trade if trade
surplus from China isn't finding itself
in the NASDAQ, that's the only reason
people were paying 50 times earnings for
companies. 50 times earnings is
irrational. It was very irrational
economic behavior that was happening.
So, Bitcoin is not a stock. uh Bitcoin
is not priced on earnings. Bitcoin is
not priced on, you know, trade surpluses
from foreign partners. And so I I do I
do think that right now everything is
tied to liquidity. But uh fund we're
returning to fundamentals. A lot of the
irrational behavior can't sustain itself
for very much longer. And that's the
volatility we're seeing today.
And you said um money is really just a
way to store human time and energy. So
if I complete this task, I get $1,000,
$10,000. So if Bitcoin keeps growing as
a store of value, how do we how do we
value both in terms of human capital and
how we price traditional assets like
stocks or real estate? How does it
reshape our view? Yeah, I think the most
uh important innovation that Satoshi
came across with Bitcoin is the proofof
work concept. It makes Bitcoin energy
money. So to your point, you I view
money as time and energy in an
abstracted form. It is the market
representation of our effort, our labor,
our time, our energy, our contribution,
our work. And so you want your money to
have a direct relationship with energy
component. An exaggerated way to explain
this is if your money doesn't have a
relationship to work in energy and you
can just print it out of thin air, then
it's highly inflationary. It could be
debased. It's a bad store of value. So
when you have an energy based money that
actually is protective and applies
physical constraints to its ability to
inflate and be receptive to an onslaught
of demand. It it actually allows us
humans to lower our time preference to
be more future oriented. If you are not
so panicked to think how am I going to
be able to afford this house? How am I
going to be able to afford this
vacation? If you are given more
confidence and an ability to save and
future plan for yourself, then society
gets generally better. Um I I think
money a weaker money means a weaker
society, a stronger money and a harder
money harder and how hard is it to
produce more units of the money
represents a stronger harder society
that's more future oriented and can plan
better for tomorrow. And you own zero
dollars, right? You said in one of your
interviews, what does that look like
running businesses? Um, well, it's
that's for me personally, but I mean, my
philosophy there is pretty
straightforward is that, you know, why
would I own something that I believe is
structurally designed to go down versus
why how much would I want to own if
something that I believe is structurally
designed to outperform because of its
scarcity property? And the answer is I I
wouldn't want to own much, if any, of
the thing that has historically only
gone down. And of the thing that's been
historically the most performant, I want
to own as much as I possibly can. And so
I use products actually that Strike has
built like I can get my paycheck in
Bitcoin with Strike. I can pay my bills
with Bitcoin and Strike. I can borrow
against my Bitcoin. So in the event that
I need fiat liquidity, I can actually
get a loan against my Bitcoin with
Strike as opposed to have to sell and
part with my Bitcoin. So, we're seeing
financial products that are making
Bitcoin more useful and allowing you to
finance different parts of your life
while retaining and saving in a money
that is designed to be protective of
your time and energy as opposed to
extort it and take advantage of it.
Yeah. But uh you know who doesn't agree
with you is Peter Schiff who you've
debated on my show um on a number of
points. First on the fact that uh
Bitcoin's value is derived from the uh
uh things that you talked about. Bitcoin
has no value. It's driven by hope and um
and expectations basically just thin
air. But the second point is that risk
isn't the same as volatility because we
were talking about how we can measure
the risk profile of Bitcoin and Bitcoin
being an asset with a very high standard
deviation is considered risky by
traditional finance me uh terms. So how
do you reconcile that difference between
risk and volatility in Bitcoin? Yeah.
Well, I think what market participants
need to understand is volatility is a
prerequisite to performance. Um, it's a
it's a necess if I need to, David, if I
walk into a building and I enter the
lobby on the first floor and I need to
get to the penthouse, my my journey
there up the elevator is inherently
volatile. I'm moving directionally up.
Now, we could bounce around a few
floors, but if I'm going to go from the
zero floor to a 100th floor, my journey
has to be volatile. It's it's physics.
The analogy that I like to tell my my
childhood friends is if you were to walk
into a doctor to get your vitals checked
and they were to say, "Jack, I'm so
sorry, but your heart rate is no
volatility." I, you know, you know, you
know your heart monitors, it's bouncing
around. It means it has life. It means
it's beating. If my heart had zero
volatility, I'd be dead. And so
volatility is life. Volatility is a
prerequisite to performance. And so, you
know, financial markets have invented
things like the sharp ratio, which is
it's a ratio that represents how much am
I getting compensated for the
volatility. If you're whipping me around
like a ragd doll, but I'm not getting
any performance on whatever I'm holding,
well, then it's not worth getting
whipped around like that. But if you're
putting me through volatility, but I'm
getting the best performing thing in
human history, then there's probably
room for that in your portfolio. Now, do
you want to go zero dollars all in like
me? That's up to you. But the idea that
volatility is the same as risk is not
true. Volatility is an ingredient in
success. Risk is the idea that the
Bitcoin network can outright fail as a
technology and everything get marked to
zero. And I would say under that
definition, Bitcoin is one of the least
risky things you can own because you can
own it without any counterparty risk. I
can own it without having to trust
anyone but math. So if my bet is that
math isn't going to get marked to zero
due to a failure, I'm cool with that
risk. And then it depends how much of
the volatility are you willing to
stomach given your portfolio. But you
know, the fact that it has volatility
means it's alive and it can be
successful. Zero volatility would be a
dead heart. You were just talking about
counterparty risk. So for an average
person holding one BTC feels a lot
scarier than keeping 100K in a bank
because the risk of losing the private
key or the hacks is a lot scarier,
right? How do you think we can fix that?
So I think the one of the most important
properties of Bitcoin is that you can
use it on your own terms. It doesn't
imply that you have to use it on your
own terms. So, it enables a truly free
market where someone can act as self-s
sovereignly as they want or trust an
instit in institution as much as they
want. You're more than welcome to open a
strike account and I'll hold your
private keys for you. Now, I don't
necessarily advocate that as the
direction society should be grinding
towards, but if that is where you are
today, there are businesses and services
that offer that product. I do
fundamentally believe that if we're
going to restore any sense of harmony to
society, it's going to rest on the idea
of personal responsibility. Again, I do
think that society has found a level of
comfort that's disadvantageous to human
harmony, which is, you know, it depends
on who gets elected if I'm happy. It
depends on the stock market if I can
afford my home. It's depends on what
they're serving in McDonald's if I'm
going to be overweight or maintain
weight. And restoring personal
responsibility in society, again, I
think is foundationally important. No
one's going to care more about you than
you. And no one owns the outcomes of
your life more than yourself. And so I
do want to encourage the idea that
owning your own property, owning your
own money, owning your own time and
energy in a self-s sovereign way, I
believe is in the best interest of every
individual, every business, every
country, every anyone. Um but you don't
have to use it that way. Bitcoin is the
only asset that gives you the freedom of
choice to the degree in which it does.
Okay. Um just on one more question on uh
Bitcoin then we'll move on to 21
Capital. So on the sharp ratio aspect,
you're correct in the sense that
Bitcoin's sharp ratio has dramatically
outperformed that of other assets over
the last 10 years. If you just take a 10
year time horizon, the sharp ratio of
Bitcoin is higher than stocks, S&P,
gold, and and bonds. And so knowing this
and knowing that financial institutions
and traditional fund managers alike care
about their risk adjusted returns, why
is their allocation to this particular
asset not higher than perhaps you might
think it is given its sharp ratio? Well,
I can't tell if you're just ingeniously
uh leading us into the 21 segment,
David, but I perhaps that's the plan,
but I can't comment. I believe uh I
believe that their allocations will
grow. Um I I think people overestimate
what can be done in a short amount of
time and underestimate what can be done
in a long amount of time. I think people
are always eager to predict that the
world is going to change in the next 24
hours and the gravity to which it can
change in the next 24 hours and they
underestimate how much can be done in a
year in a decade. And so I think the
size of these institutions, how they're
governed, the bureaucracy that's
involved in changes, it just takes a
second. But a lot of what I see uh
personally is a growing demand from
institutions and a massive appetite for
Bitcoin in the capital markets and I
think their position sizing is only
growing. So why don't we just talk about
uh this new development and I'll let you
kind of just tell the story here. So
this is from FT but it it made the news
all over the news. You're on Bloomberg
last week talking about this. Caner
strikes $3.6 billion crypto deal with
SoftBank and Tether. Uh Brandon Lutnick,
son of US commerce secretary Howard
Lutick is partnering with SoftBank,
Tether and Bitfinex on a Bitcoin
acquisition vehicle to capitalize on a
currency revival under President Trump.
This is called 21 Capital. You are the
co-founder and CEO. Just tell us about
the genesis of this idea leading up
until this announcement. The vehicle
will launch with 42,000 Bitcoin. It's
going to be one of the largest uh
treasuries in the world for Bitcoin. How
did you get Lutnik and Soft Bank and
Tether and Bitfinex all together on
this? Yeah, you know, this is the first
podcast I've done in any long form since
I appreciate it. We're honored to have
you here. Yeah. So, I actually um am
really excited to tell, you know, some
of the founding story. This is the first
time I'll be able to share it in a more
public forum. Um so, for the audience,
21 exists purely to give the world a new
kind of public company, one that's built
entirely around Bitcoin. We consider
ourselves one of, if not the most pure
play public equity or attempting to
become a public equity uh in the market.
The founding story. So uh I co-founded
the business with Tether. Uh just so
everyone know I've been friends with
Tether for a very long time. Uh I don't
think people know I've been in Bitcoin
for almost 13 years. Um I believe the
some of the Tether and Bitfinex founders
have been in Bitcoin longer than I have.
So, we've been friends just because
David, there weren't that many people in
Bitcoin that long ago. You know, the the
meetups with free pizza and beer um
where you were buying uh Papa John's
pies just to see if anyone else in your
neighborhood was into Bitcoin. There
were only nine or 10 people at those
meetups. So, I've known the Tether folks
for a really long time. I think uh our
most famed overlap is El Salvador. I was
obviously a material part of that story
and the legal tender law. And then
Tether is now headquartered there,
doiciled there. They've become a
material part of El Salvador's Bitcoin
journey as well. And so I would say
Tether and I have always philosophically
aligned on what this technology means.
We both serve products in emerging
markets like Africa, like Latin America.
So been very philosophically aligned and
been friends for a very long time. I
would say four or five years ago when
Michael Sailor started Micro Strategy
and his pivot into Bitcoin, I mean, we
were both we were inspired. We were just
in awe. I mean, Bitcoin inspires some of
the most creative thinking I've ever
seen. Um, it was so brilliant. It was so
clever. Uh, it was so powerful of a
concept. And as Bitcoiners, we were
like, "Let's go. This is amazing." And I
would say maybe, uh, few years go by,
maybe one to two years ago, that
slightly started to change from, "Wow,
this is so cool. How fun is this as
Bitcoiners to hey, you know, there's a
lot of growing institutional demand for
Bitcoin that we as OG Bitcoiners could
have only dreamed of. There's a massive
capital markets appetite for Bitcoin,
and we were maybe underwhelmed is not
the right way to say it, but we we
thought Bitcoin could be represented in
the capital markets in a different and
potentially better way. And that was
more recently when we've seen a lot of
micro strategyesque businesses. They're
a bit smaller cap. All of these
companies are pivoting from a prior
business, a business that maybe wasn't
working, a business that was maybe
failed. Not a lot of the leadership
teams have experience in Bitcoin, have
built high margin, high growth, cash
flow generating products, have
contributed to the protocol. And so as
we saw ETFs get approved, as we saw
Bitcoin continue to march on as an
institutional-grade asset, our friend
our our conversations over the campfire,
so to speak, started to change from,
wow, isn't this fun to follow as a
Bitcoiner to, hey, you know, we think
maybe we can provide what the capital
markets need in our opinion and the
appetite that they're building. And it
got to a point was who better than us?
Who better than myself, Tether? people
that are Bitcoiners, know how to build
and work in this industry, and feel like
we have the blue chip credibility and
can bring some startup upside to the
capital markets in a very pure play way.
And so we sat around the analogous
campfire and we're like, what should we
call it? And I love the name 20 21
because XXI, the ticker was available,
uh 21 in Roman numerals. And so I say, I
really like this name because again, we
are a Bitcoin business. We're founded as
such. We're not pivoting. We're not
rebranding. We're not trying to find 21
million Bitcoin cap. Is that the 21
million? Yes. Yes. And I thought I
thought it was very adjacent and clever
and sexy and again it was Bitcoin. It
was Bitcoin. And so then uh I made
mention we were like how much capital
should we seed the business with? And if
you look at our public filings actually
um between Bitfinex and Tether, if you
add their initial um seeding, it's
21,000 Bitcoin. And so that 21,000
number because I was like, "Guys, 21's
our number. We got, you know, memes rule
the world. We got to go to the market.
We're going to have 21,000 coins. Our
name's going to be 21. Our ticker uh
hopefully if we get approved is 21 in
Roman numerals." And that's the founding
story is we what we wanted to bring to
the market, David, was blue chip
credibility, startupside. We feel like
we are big enough to win, small enough
to grow. And being a pure play Bitcoin
company founded by OG technologists in
the space that have a lot of prior
success in their other businesses. I
mean, Tether for sure is probably the
most profitable per employee company in
the history of our species. And Strike
on a gross and net profit per employee
is is up there with the best of them, if
not the best in the Bitcoin space. And
so, we feel like we can actually extend
the treasury opportunity beyond just
buying Bitcoin and actually building on
top of it. And so, that was the initial
founding. Soft Bank was actually our
first outside investor. I don't know if
people know this. And so, we got a phone
call from the SoftBank team and said,
"Hey, you know, we we believe we
understand Bitcoin. and we understand
the thesis and if we're understanding
what you're building at 21, it's, you
know, the furthest to take our dollar, a
dollar into 21 goes far further in
theory than in ETF. And we want to get
to know the team and we want to get to
know the plan. And it actually was very
validating for us as founders of the
business because it cemented this idea
of we're bringing blue chip credibility,
massive capital partners with a lot of
experience and credibility in financial
markets with startup upside with the
ability to build technology on top of
this asset class with an ability to
accumulate in an accretive bitcoin per
share sense. And so SoftBank joined us
and came on board as our first outside
investor and then working with Caner um
both on the banking side and on the spa
side. They've been such a
forwardthinking financial partner on
Wall Street when it comes to crypto and
to Bitcoin. And so it was a natural
partnership for us and that's what's
gotten me to this podcast. That's that's
really a lot of the story. Um and we're
planning to go to market with over
42,000 Bitcoin uh at approval. Um you
are creating some Bitcoin products,
right?
Yeah. So again, I think I would say, you
know, the opportunity in the market that
we saw is there's a lot of really small
cap, smallsiz businesses that we don't
think are institutional grade or can
represent Bitcoin in an institutional
capacity. And that those are maybe not
the micro strategies of the world. And
so we wanted to bring bluechip
credibility in initial size. So, we're
coming to the market with billions of
dollars worth of Bitcoin, a lot of
capital behind us in partnerships,
access to Wall Street, a lot of
experience. We know what we're doing.
But then the startup upside is that, you
know, we didn't see anyone take this
Bitcoin treasury opportunity and
actually build products. Um, all all
we've seen is people just buying
Bitcoin. And as Bitcoin technologists
and folks that have contributed to the
protocol and helped build this industry,
we know where the high margin high
growth opportunities are. We know how to
scale and build this technology. And so
we're very excited to take access to the
capital markets and to our our Bitcoin
treasury, which is a unique asset on our
balance sheet, and actually build and
extend beyond just owning. And and we
think we're very unique in a pure
Bitcoin play that's going to bring both
technology and access to capital markets
and a creative bitcoin per share growth.
What can we expect? Anything any
timeline and next steps you can share
with us? Um, so, so I I think what
everyone should know is that what we
announced was a filing and an intent to
go public um through a spa merger with
Caner Equity Partners, but uh that has
not been approved. And so what we
consider our first product is the equity
itself. And so we're very hopeful to
launch that first product on a stock
exchange and that's the ticker XXI. But
that has not been approved. And so
really a lot of my job today at 21 is
both working with regulators and
partners upon that approval process and
trying to educate everyone on the
business and get XXI listed on a stock
exchange someday and then also coming
and hanging out with you two lovely
people and educating the world on why
Bitcoin matters and what why we're doing
is different and and we think really
powerful for those in capital markets
that want to participate in Bitcoin. And
if I could just jump in here. So, one of
the concerns with the with any vehicle,
not just yours, but with any
institutional level vehicle acquiring
large numbers of Bitcoin, is the issue
of decentralization. So, you probably
heard this a million times already, but
I'll ask it anyway. How can we still
protect individual sovereignty and the
decentralization ethos, which is at the
heart of owning Bitcoin when you've got
large entities like Soft Bank and
Tether, which was previously known for
stable coins, but I guess is now going
to be known for this as well. How do we
protect sovereignty and decentralization
when you've got 42,000 bitcoins
announced on your treasury? Yeah. Well,
I think um an important piece for
listeners to understand is that the way
the Bitcoin protocol is designed, you
don't have any more or less influence
based on how much Bitcoin you own.
Everyone should know that. Um that
actually is a proofofstake network. So
networks that use proof of stake, you
actually grow or lessen in influence
depending on how much of the currency
unit you own. That's not true for
Bitcoin. So the fact that Michael Sailor
and Micro Strategy own as much Bitcoin
as they do, that actually doesn't give
him any more outside influence on the
protocol itself. So all of the
sovereignty and individual rights that
the Bitcoin protocol operates and
defends within its distributed network
retain and remain the same. And that's a
really really important design of the
actual technology itself. So it doesn't
matter how much of a currency unit like
Bitcoin someone owns, they don't have
any extra influence. So I'll open and
start with that. Um and then I think
just on the wider question of you know
Wall Street entering Bitcoin, what does
this mean for the project? Isn't that
counter to the ethos of Satoshi? Uh in
my opinion, Bitcoin is a permissionless
network. It's a permissionless money.
It's a money that in theory enemies can
use to settle together. And so it's very
in its nature that if anyone wants to
buy Bitcoin, they can. Today we live in
a macro environment where Wall Street
and fixed income investors, there's a
lot of people that are looking for
performance in real terms. And there's a
lot of capital and a lot of money and a
lot of demand for something that is
inelastic in its supply demand dynamics.
And so they can buy Bitcoin just like
anyone else. I find it a bit
hypocritical that Bitcoiners can say, "I
don't like them buying Bitcoin. Kick
them out." You can't kick anyone out of
Bitcoin. Bitcoin doesn't have a ruler or
governing body that gets to decide who
gets to own it. So, it's very important
in the protocol's design that the way
Satoshi built Bitcoin is anyone can come
and buy it. Anyone can buy as much as
they want and everyone gets the same
rules and the the same power within the
network to enforce and defend those
rules. Okay. And just on the aspect of
the um the company itself, first of all,
are is it going to be are you planning
to make it public like it's going to be
like a stock of 21 Capital? Yeah. So, uh
21 what we announced and is a filing?
So, uh is a a spa. So, we've partnered
with Caner Equity Partners and we've
filed to list our stock on a stock
exchange in a public manner, but it is
not approved. And it's super important
the audience knows that we're in the
approval process now. Um, but our goal
is to list the stock under ticker XXI
publicly on a stock exchange. Yes. And
an investor were to say, well, it's a
peer play acquisition vehicle. uh the
company is going to be you know the
valuation of this particular listing is
going to be based a lot if not mostly on
Bitcoin. Do you plan to hedge at all?
Going back to the previous question of
volatility if Bitcoin goes down you know
would investors want you to hedge
somehow? Uh no. So uh upon our filing I
encourage everyone to read it if they
have the time is uh we introduced two
new metrics to the financial markets to
where in which we want to be judged. The
first is Bitcoin per share BPS and that
is to replace the traditional financial
market metric earnings per share EPS and
then the other is BRR which is a little
clever play on BUR or money printer go
Burr but it stands for Bitcoin return
rate uh and it is to replace a metric
like ARR and the reason and in our
filing what we encourage market
participants to judge us on is actually
in Bitcoin performance. So my mandate
and my my goal to our shareholders and
to the wider financial markets, David,
is to be able to grow our Bitcoin per
share. So in a hypothetical sense, let's
say our Bitcoin P per share is 0.05
Bitcoin per share. That that's the
amount of Bitcoin on our balance sheet
on a per fully diluted share basis. Our
intent as a company is to be able to
work to grow that to 0.6 Bitcoin per
share, 0.7 Bitcoin per share. And we
want the markets to judge us on being
performant in Bitcoin terms. It's a
capital markets vehicle that's designed
to outperform Bitcoin. And so our time
horizon with Bitcoin is forever. We
don't ever plan on hedging or selling
any Bitcoin. And we want the markets to
not judge us necess like our
shareholders we believe are Bitcoiners
and they just want a growing amount of
exposure to Bitcoin. They want the most
effective capital markets vehicle to
participate in Bitcoin. And so we've
created these new metrics that actually
measure us not in fiat, which we think
is the old world, but in Bitcoin because
we don't believe we're here to beat the
existing market. We believe we're here
to build a new market and build a new
financial system. And we hear a lot
about how Wall Street has arrived in
Bitcoin with IBIT and with Black Rockck.
And I would say with 21, uh, Bitcoin has
arrived on Wall Street. and we plan on
uh performing in Bitcoin terms and in
retaining and sticking and promoting to
the principles of Bitcoin. It's a
compounding growth uh feature. So here
you've you've announced it on your own
YouTube channel. I didn't I didn't even
know you have a YouTube channel but
anyway um I guess people should follow
Jack Mers. But um you announced this
last week can you just talk about this
slide comparing 21 to spot Bitcoin ETF?
I think this is pretty key. Like why
should we even consider this?
When when you invest in 21 and and you
buy a share of the business, you again
hypothetical sense. Our intent is to
grow the Bitcoin per share. You're
investing in an operating company.
You're investing in a leadership team to
execute. And you know that leadership in
part is me. And what we do is we go out
and access capital markets and raise
capital in a creative Bitcoin terms. We
go out and build partnerships. We go out
and build products, build cash flow, all
correlated and related to Bitcoin to
grow that Bitcoin per share. So our
mandate to our shareholders is by owning
a share in the company. Our intent is to
grow your access to Bitcoin just by
being an investor, just by being a
shareholder. If you contrast that to a
vehicle like an ETF, an ETF is static
exposure. When you buy IBIT, the Black
Rockck ETF, you're not investing in
Larry Frink and Black Rockck to go out
and grow your Bitcoin per IBIT share. If
you start with 0.05 BTC and IBIT, you
end with 0.05 BTC and IBIT. It is a
static exposure vehicle where 21 is a
business. And so that is what we think
is attractive to investors into the
capital markets is a pure play blue chip
credibility with startup upside vehicle
in the capital markets that's just
working at all cost to grow that Bitcoin
per share. And in the near term, we're
not really bothered by the BTC USD price
because we know if we're able to
accretively grow Bitcoin and Bitcoin
goes on to achieve what we believe it
can in changing the world that uh both
ourselves and our shareholders will be
happy. Okay. And just kind of linking
this to Strike uh which you're currently
CEO of, do you see any I guess
collaboration or um uh sort of merging
of features between 21 and Strike? No,
these are two independent businesses. I
mean, the only uh shared overlap is the
desire to promote Bitcoin and support it
in changing the world in what we believe
is the right direction. But they're
entirely separate businesses. So, uh
founder, CEO of Strike, co-founder, CEO
of 21. I'll run and lead both
businesses, but independently. Uh you
know, I think where Strike stands and
leads and continues to grow is in
Bitcoin financial services. So, Strike
faces the consumer and we provide
financial services like a loan, like
being able to buy and sell Bitcoin,
custody your Bitcoin, move your Bitcoin
around the world. And we're really
focused on making Bitcoin more useful
and integrated into someone's everyday
life. Like an amazing strike customer
story recently is as we're rolling out
collateralized loans against Bitcoin. We
had a customer call and say, "Hey, uh my
daughter wants to get a house because um
we're going to have our first
grandchild, but uh we're having a tough
time making the down payment. Can I
borrow against my Bitcoin so I can
retain our savings and retain this
instrument that's performing at a 40 50%
compound annual growth rate, but get
access to some of the liquidity so that
I can help my daughter out?" And that's
the type of stories that strike enables
with its consumer financial services.
21's a totally different business with
totally different goals in mind which is
giving capital markets what we believe
the ultimate vehicle to participate in
Bitcoin and its story. So two
independent uh businesses the the only
overlap is is Bitcoin and how much each
business believes in it. on strike. Um,
help me visualize how are you executing
the vision in countries with unstable
currencies or weak banking in
infrastructure. Yeah. So, strike uh we
consider each region of the world almost
as a different product line. Um, because
you're right, uh, there's different
markets, different extremities,
different conditions. So, we have strike
US, strike EU, and strike UK. Those all
operate with the local currency. So we
do support the dollar, the euro and the
pound natively. And then in some of the
markets in Latin America and Africa, the
currencies are so weak and our customers
don't even want to hold them to where in
which we offer stable coins. So we
actually do offer USDT in those markets.
And so some of our products in emerging
markets are stable coin plus bitcoin and
then some of our products in more
developed markets are the local currency
plus bitcoin. And at strike we really
pride ourselves on being so customer
focused. We try and take the ego out of
being a financial services provider and
we don't task ourselves with predicting
the future or knowing what people want.
We just shut up and listen and what our
customers tell us what they want is what
we build. And that's how we've become a
successful business is just by being
egoless and being good listeners. And so
what we've learned is in the emerging
markets, people love stable coins. And
in the developed markets, people want um
higher quality financial services
integrated into something like their
Chase account and ability to borrow
against their Bitcoin and finance a down
payment, finance starting a new
business, finance an emergency surgery.
So, different markets in that respect um
with a similar ethos and product
structure.
Do you have any changes to your strategy
uh given that uh Trump won I think last
time we spoke you and I was before the
inauguration.
So, I'm I'm just wondering if a more
crypto friendly administration has
changed the way you do business. I mean,
listen, there's just no doubt that an
administration that was debanking folks
and actively against the industry versus
an administration that's supportive of
not only the cryptocurrency space, but
more broadly deregulation. They're
focused on growth. They're focused on
innovation across all tech sectors.
There's just no doubt that that is a
better environment for an entrepreneur
like myself to build here in the United
States of America. But I don't consider
Bitcoin Strike 21, I don't consider any
of it a political trade. Meaning, it
doesn't really matter who's in office.
It doesn't really matter what a
politician says. I'll tell you this,
David, if if Bitcoin was reliant on
Trump saying the right thing, I wouldn't
own it. I wouldn't own it. And and nor
do I think a lot of people that own it
today would own it. And so I I consider
Bitcoin apolitical in that sense. It's
been successful no matter who's been in
office. And you know, I'm not taking a
stance on left verse right, red verse
blue, up verse down. Um, I think no
matter what, there's a lot of good that
can be done with this technology and
Bitcoin will continue to be successful.
But no, of course, I mean, the fact that
the United States seems to align and
understand the potential and power of
this technology and how it aligns with
American ideals, I think that's a great
thing. As an American, I want to raise
my kids here someday. And I'm happy that
we're thinking about the fiscal deficit
problems and and uh and the debt and
using something like Bitcoin to
incorporate in our plans, I think, is
exciting. Well, I'll give you an
example. So the Fed as an example
recently I believe changed one of their
uh regulations so that they banks
traditional banks no longer need uh to
file uh uh separately with the Fed if
they want to include crypto products in
their lineup. So I think they're
removing one step in the vetting
process. So, I'm just saying
hypothetically, if we were to get an
administration that allows traditional
financial companies to basically do what
you're doing right now with Strike, um,
would that change your strategy at all?
Basically, a more crypto friendly
environment also opens up the door to
more competition, is it not? Uh, yeah,
but I I would say not necessarily. Um, I
I don't think what banks and traditional
financial institutions are good at is
what Strike is good at. Um, you know, I
I understand from the highest level
possible, we both serve finances and
more people might know who Chase Bank is
more than they know who I am. But in the
nitty-gritty bolts of actually building
a business, I don't think Jamie Diamond
is nearly as good as me at Bitcoin,
building these type of products,
distributing these products,
articulating these products. And so, you
know, I I think you could have made the
same case 5 years ago when I started
Strike, and I had every excuse to not
build the business, but it turns out
it's a lot harder than it looks. Um, and
it takes, you know, a certain type of
pioneering and understanding the asset
and developing really niche and and rare
engineering capabilities to pull some of
this stuff off. So, you know, for for me
it's, you know, keep your head down,
focus on yourself. There's a lot more
you can do um with narrowed focus uh and
focusing internally than externally and
kind of cheating off everyone else's
homework. So, we'll see. You know, if
Jamie Diamond is the best Bitcoin bank
next month, I'll come back on the show
and give you my opinion, but uh I'm
highly skeptical of that. All right, we
have a few more Bitcoin questions to
close off and then uh I think that'll
wrap up a good discussion. Cool. The
next one needs a little imagination. So,
we all know that Bitcoin has this 21
million cap and it's protected by this
decentralized consensus uh users,
miners, nodes, developers, and no single
group um can change a rule, right? But
let's imagine this world. Is there any
possibility any possibility that if
governments or big institutions they
hold more and more bitcoins and they
somehow use the reason of national
security reasons or they just somehow
join forces and pressure miners majority
of nodes and exchanges could they
actually push through a change to the
total supply? I can't pinpoint why
anybody would do that, but I just want
to know if there is a slight chance. Uh,
no. So, the way Bitcoin works is the
rules are enforced by anyone that wants
to download and run them. And so, it
actually would be fairly difficult, if
not impossible, for even if Trump were
to come out and say, "Turn all those
off." you know, what are we gonna I
mean, he'd have to you'd have to go in
every individual home, find every
individual device that decided to
download and run this software um to
actually change the rules. What we've
seen is when people change the rules in
Bitcoin, they just create different
versions of Bitcoin. So, there's you've
probably heard of Bitcoin uh Cash,
Bitcoin Blue, Bitcoin Wood, Bitcoin Sky,
and these are just versions of Bitcoin
where someone wanted to change the rules
to maybe benefit themselves. And those
things actually trend toward zero. the
value is in an apolitical neutral money.
And so by even trying to change the
rules, you destruct the the very value
of the network. So I'll say that uh to
your other point though of why someone
would want to do that, there's actually
game theory design in Bitcoin where
you're incentivized to act in the best
interest of the asset. You know, people
often say, what if a nation state
accumulates so much energy where they
want to 51% attack Bitcoin? We've
actually seen governments and nation
states actually instead of 51% attacking
Bitcoin, they just start mining Bitcoin
because, you know, it's a way better
idea than double spending my transaction
when I bought pizza just mining a ton of
Bitcoin because it's valuable. So,
there's actually a game theoretical
element to Bitcoin where you're incented
to act in its best interest because you
get paid to. Like, why would you destroy
a $2 trillion network instead of just
buy it and grow it to four trillion,
right? Why would you attack a network by
double spending one random transaction
instead of using all this energy that
your country has access to and just
mining a ton of it and paying off your
debt? So, you're right in that you it's
very counterintuitive to find the
incentive structure for someone to
attack Bitcoin because it's in their
benefit to adopt it. And even if they
were to attack it, um it's very unclear
to me how they could do that
successfully at any scale. What's a
belief that you had about Bitcoin from
your earliest days that you completely
outgrown?
Oh man, I I think uh you know for me
Bitcoin has been a a education vehicle
for money more broadly. uh and uh maybe
my belief in initially what I thought
maybe made Bitcoin valuable and I saw
Bitcoin as a competitor to PayPal and
when I realized that you know Bitcoin is
competing in the free market of storing
humans time and energy and allowing us
to exchange and price our collective
efforts um and just what money as a
technology has brought to humanity
allowing us to hyper specialize and
exceed something like barter um that is
something that when I was an 18-year-old
kid and getting into Bitcoin, I I had no
idea uh the the profoundness of money
and how important a hard money was to a
functioning society, which now it's a
guiding principle and day-to-day
decisions I make about myself. So, I
would say my understanding of money,
Bitcoin, I owe that to Bitcoin for sure.
My last question to you, Jack, and we'll
close it off here. Are you still buying
your pizzas with Bitcoin? All
right. So, what I do is uh and I I
encourage everyone to just try and
understand this concept and and it might
apply to you and be interesting. I spend
my entire life on credit cards, which is
an interesting product because I get to
spend dollars without having to own
them, right? Banks effectively give me a
30-day line of credit for free. And then
I use Strike to take a loan against my
Bitcoin and and bill pay to pay off the
credit cards. So, I actually just keep
acquiring Bitcoin with my paychecks. And
whether I'm borrowing against the
Bitcoin to get dollars or I'm actually
paying the bills with Strike's bill pay
service. Then I'm never owning dollars.
I my Visa and Mastercards, they're
accepted everywhere. So, it's not like
my quality of life gets lower or
lessened because I can only shop at the
Bitcoin coffee shop. So, I run around
with my credit cards. I spend on a free
line of credit from banks and I just
stack Bitcoin and uh enjoy life. But
you're still effectively buying your
pizza with fiat because you're using
credit card. But if somebody were to
offer you, let's say, a slice of pizza
and say it's worth 0.0, whatever the
case may be, Bitcoin, would you would
you do it? Would you exchange Bitcoin
for a consumable good in 2025? I'm a
supporter. I'm a supporter of the
network, but I think what you're asking
is would I spend Bitcoin as opposed to
dollars in the Yeah. Would you spend
good money, let's say, for a consumable
depreciating good? No, of course not. I
mean, the good the game is, you know,
hoard the better money, get rid of the
weaker money. And I think there's just
been a guiding principle that since
Bitcoin has existed. If you've saved in
Bitcoin, looking at historical data,
your life has gotten cheaper. I actually
was on a podcast not too long ago, a
median home in the US was 1.8 million
bitcoins. 1.8 million bitcoins. So,
you'd have to have two Satoshi stacks of
Bitcoin to get a median home in the US
in 2011. And now a median host house
today in the United States is 4.7
bitcoin. So obviously if you're saving
in a harder money then the life around
you has historically gotten cheaper and
if you're saving in a money that's
increasingly abundant like fiat your
life has has gotten more expensive.
Obviously the median uh home in the
America has gone up in US dollar terms.
So no I I hoard the hard money and I I
spend the abundant inflated money. Well
that was a great uh great rep. So, I
look forward to having pizza with you in
Vegas.
Yes. Bonnie and I both um we'll be
covering the BTC Vegas and you'll be a
speaker. So, tell us where we can find
you and follow you in the interim. Yeah,
so strike is strike.me. That's our
website. 21 is
xxi.money. So, you can go find more
information about the businesses there.
And Jack Malers is my real name. I am
not hiding behind a pseudonym. So, um,
all my profiles are Jack Morers and, uh,
and I I'll see everyone on the internet.
Okay, great. Thank you very much. Thank
you both. We'll see you next time. See
you.